monster.co.uk 2006-12-18

# Monster.co.uk: Privacy and Cookies

Privacy and Cookies

**Monster.co.uk's Privacy and Cookies - Overview**

This web site is operated by Monster as described below. Monster is committed to protecting the privacy of our users. We strive to provide a safe, secure user experience. The aim of this Statement is to inform you how we will use any personal data which you provide through this web site and does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion. This Statement is aimed at job seekers and employers. 

Monster complies with data protection legislation. This regulates the processing of information relating to you and grants you various rights in respect of your personal data. Our sites contain links to other web sites over which we have no control. Monster is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other web sites to which you choose to link from this site. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other web sites so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information. This Privacy Statement applies solely to the information we collect on this web site and does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion. 

**Collection and Retention of Information**

You do not have to give us any personal information in order to perform job searches. In some areas of our web site, Monster requests that you provide personal data, including your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number, contact information, billing information and other information from which your identity is discernible. In other areas of our web site, Monster collects or may collect demographic information that is not unique to you such as your postcode, age, gender and the types of work in which you are interested. Sometimes we collect or may collect a combination of the two types of information. Examples of areas on this site where we collect personal or combined personal and demographic data are pages where you can open a MyMonster account, sign up to use a service, post a CV, enter a contest or purchase a product. In each case, it is indicated on the web site whether any data must be provided to use the required service or not. 

In addition, Monster may indirectly collect information about you when you use certain third party services on our web site. For example, if you register on our site by using your Microsoft Passport user name and password, you authorise us to have access to and store the information in your Passport account profile; such information will be subject to, and treated in accordance with, the policies and practices described in this Statement. 

We also gather or may gather certain personal information about your use of our site, such as what areas you visit and what services you access. Moreover, there is information about your computer hardware and software that is or may be collected by Monster. This information may include your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring web site addresses, but is not linked to your personal information. 

We may sometimes afford you the opportunity to provide descriptive, cultural, behavioural, preferential and/or life style information about yourself but it is solely up to you whether you furnish such information. If you do provide such information, you are thereby consenting to the use of that information in accordance with the policies and practices described in this Privacy Statement. For example, such information may be used for the purpose of determining your potential interest in receiving e-mail or other communications about particular products or services. 

If you use our facilities to build a CV to put in our database of jobseekers’ CVs, then you will be providing us with personal data which we will use in accordance with this Statement. We strongly suggest that your CV should not contain data relating to your (i) racial or ethnic origin (ii) political beliefs (iii) philosophical or religious beliefs (iv) membership of a trade union or political party (v) physical or mental health (vi) sexual life or (vii) the commission of criminal offences or proceedings. If your CV does contain such data, then you agree that we may retain this information and use it in accordance with this Statement. 

**Posting to Public Areas of Monster**

Please remember that if you post any of your personal information in public areas of Monster, such as in online forums or chat rooms, or in the searchable CV database, such information may be collected and used by others over whom Monster has no control. We are not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of Monster. 

**Use of Your Information by Monster**

We use the information we gather on the web site whether personal, demographic, collective or technical, for the purposes of administering and managing your registration, responding to any queries you may have, operating and improving the web site, fostering a positive user experience and delivering the products and services that we offer to jobseekers and employers. 

If you have so agreed when registering with Monster or subsequently or if permitted by applicable law, we may use your contact information in order to send you e-mail or other communications regarding updates at the web site, such as new Monster opportunities and additional listings which may be of interest to you. In addition, at the time of registration for MyMonster, you have the option to elect to receive additional communications, information and promotions including, without limitation, free informational newsletters from Monster relating to topics that may be of special interest to you, such as career management advice. If you have so consented or if permitted by applicable law, we may also use the information we gather to inform you of other products or services available from Monster or its affiliated companies (as defined below) or to contact you about your opinion of current products and services or potential new products and services that may be offered. 

We have an area where you can contact us and submit feedback. We may use such feedback (such as success stories) for promotional purposes or to contact you for further information. 

**Disclosure of Information to Others**

We do not disclose to third parties your personal information, combined personal and demographic information or information about your use of the web site (such as the areas you visit or the services you access), except as set forth below. 

  1. We may disclose such information to third parties if you consent to such disclosure. For example, if you make your CV searchable, then all parties with access to our searchable CV database (or copies thereof) will have access to that database. You may make your CV unsearchable at any time. 
  2. We may disclose such information to companies and individuals we employ to perform functions on our behalf including data processors and including companies and individuals located outside the European Economic Area. The functions performed on our behalf include hosting our web servers, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments and providing customer service. These companies and individuals will have access to your personal information as necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party or use that data for any other purpose. We will retain control of and be responsible for any information shared in this way. 
  3. We may disclose such information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or regulatory authority or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of Monster or its affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. 
  4. We may disclose and transfer such information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of Monster's business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event Monster becomes the subject of an insolvency proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, Monster or its liquidator, administrator, receiver or administrative receiver may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the court. You will be notified of sale of all or a substantial portion of our business to a third party by email or through a prominent notice posted on the Monster site. 

**Other Uses of Information**

Monster may also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to its web sites with its clients, partners and other third parties so that they may understand the kinds of visitors to Monster's site and how those visitors use the site. 

Monster supplies technology, hosting and related services to other leading companies to power recruitment areas on their web sites (sometimes referred to as " hosted career sites"). Personal and/or demographic information supplied by you in hosted career site areas becomes part of the Monster CV database, but it is not accessible by anyone other than you, Monster and the company concerned without your consent. However, if you attempt to register with Monster after registering with a hosted career site, Monster will recognise your account details and you will be able to retrieve the information already provided by you in your MyMonster account registration with the hosted career site. 

Information gathered on a page in a hosted career site area or on a co-branded page may be retained by both Monster and the other company. In that instance, the use of such information by the other company may be subject to the privacy policy of that company and, in any event, Monster is not responsible for that company's use of your personal or demographic information. 

If you apply for a position through a hosted career site or a co-branded site, you may be asked to provide information on your age, gender or race where permitted by law. You should understand that, if provided, this information should only be used by employers in accordance with applicable law. However, Monster is not responsible for the actions of such employers. All such information provided will be kept separate by Monster from your expression of interest in any job opportunity. Providing this information is strictly voluntary and you will not be subject to any adverse action or treatment from Monster if you choose not to provide this information. 

Your personal data will be stored and processed on computers in the United States as described below. The information we gather on any Monster web site may be shared within the Monster group of companies on a worldwide basis in order to deliver the products and services we offer to employers such as assisted searches for jobseekers or in order to undertake analysis of our database such as aggregated profiling of our registered users. The Monster network is detailed on the homepage of Monster.co.uk. 

Furthermore, some of the employers or employment agencies that are interested in your CV may be located outside of the European Economic Area on a worldwide basis. Such countries may not have equivalent data protection legislation protecting the use of your personal data. We will not send your personal data to these employers in these countries unless you have indicated that you would like your CV to be searchable. By providing this indication, you expressly consent to such transfers of data occurring. 

**CVs**

Since Monster is a career site, we give you the option of putting your CV in our database. There are two ways of doing this: 

  1. You can store your CV in our database, but not allow it to be searchable by potential employers. Not allowing your CV to be searchable means that you can use it to apply for a job online, but employers and recruiters will not have access to search it through our CV database product. 
  2. If you allow your CV to be searchable, then all parties with access to our searchable CV database (or copies thereof) will have access to your CV. You can also allow your CV to be searchable but remove your contact details. However, you should be aware that in this situation if you have a rare skill, it may still be possible for a recruiter to identify you even without your contact details being included. If you are worried about being identified, you should not include specific skill or details by which you could be identified. 

We attempt to limit access to our searchable CV database (or copies thereof) only to paying employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters and human resource professionals, as well as law enforcement and national security agencies, but cannot guarantee that other parties will not gain access to this database. We are not responsible for the use made of CVs by third parties who access such CVs while they are in our searchable database. You may remove your CV from our searchable database at any time, details of how to do this are given below. However, employers, recruiters and others who have paid for access to that database or to obtain a copy of that database, as well as parties who have otherwise gained access to the database may have retained a copy of your CV in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use or privacy of CVs or profiles in these instances. 

If you provide us with details of a referee, it is your responsibility to ensure that the person is aware that you have forwarded his/her details and has consented in writing for you to do so. 

**Use of Web Beacons/Javascript**

Monster web pages may contain electronic images known as web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) that allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Web beacons are not used to access your personally identifiable information on Monster; they are a technique we use to compile aggregated statistics about our web site usage. 

Web beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the web beacon resides. 

Because web beacons are the same as any other content request included in the recipe page, you cannot opt out or refuse them. However, they can be rendered ineffective by either opting out of cookies or changing the cookie setup in your browser. For details of how to do this, see our Use of Cookies Statement below. 

Third parties are not permitted to use web beacons on the Monster sites. 

Monster also may use JavaScript. JavaScript is a script language that enhaces the functionality of websites, particularly in respect to pictures. We use JavaScript for example within certain advertisements. We are not collecting any personal data via JavaScript but use it to inform employers about the conversion rate of their job ads (.i.e. how many applicants have clicked on embedded email addresses). You may deactivate JavaScript via your browser settings or activate it the same way. If you disable JavaScript you will not be able to use some of the functions of the website. 

**Updating or Deleting Your Information**

You may review, correct, update or change your MyMonster account profile information or CV at any time. Simply log into your MyMonster account, go to your Account Profile or CV, review your account information or CV and, if you wish, edit it with the options provided. You may also delete your CV through this method. 

If you wish to delete your My Monster account profile information at any time, please contact us at userservices@monster.co.uk. An email will be sent to you to confirm that your information has been deleted (save for an archival copy which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Internet). The archival copy is retained indefinitely for audit and record purposes. 

If you wish to revoke your consent to our Privacy Statement, please contact us at userservices@monster.co.uk. However, please note that if you do withdraw your consent, you may not be able to use the relevant services and your My Monster account profile information will be deleted. 

If you opted to receive newsletters, commercial e-mails or other communications from Monster or third parties at the time you registered with MyMonster, but subsequently change your mind, you may opt-out by editing your Account Profile as described above. If you previously opted not to receive such communications, you may later opt-in by editing your Account Profile. 

You may access all your personal data stored and processed by Monster and may correct, update or delete such information by contacting us at [userservices@monster.co.uk](mailto:userservices@monster.co.uk). 

Since we believe that managing your career is a life-long process, we retain all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical and relevant until you change or remove your personal data as detailed above. If you are a job seeker and have not logged onto the web site for 18 months, then we will automatically make your CV unsearchable. Of course, you can correct or update your MyMonster account profile and CV at any time. Moreover, you can delete your CV from Monster's online database or close your MyMonster account at any time. If you do this, we will remove all our copies of your CV or MyMonster account profile information except for an archival copy retained indefinitely for audit and records purposes which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Internet. Details of how to do this are set out above. 

**Security**

Monster has implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorised access, use, alteration or disclosure. In particular, all account and password data is encrypted (i.e. it is scrambled between your computer and Monsters’ servers) and all traffic which is internal to the Monster network (such as billing information and Monster’s access to our database) is also encrypted. Notwithstanding such measures, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that unauthorised third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. You should be aware that CV’s you complete at your current place of work may be monitored by your current employer. 

When you place an order online at Monster, your credit card information is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol. SSL makes it difficult for your credit card information to be intercepted or stolen while being transmitted. Monster uses a service company to process its credit card transactions. For further information on this company’s privacy and security practices, please click here. 

**Children**

Monster is not intended for children under 16 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16.

**Safe Harbor**

We participate in the US Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Framework arising out of the U.S. implementation of the European Union Data Protection Directive. Monster Worldwide Inc., Monster, Inc. and Monster Worldwide Technologies LLC have certified adherence to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles for each of the Monster Sites. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor web site. If you would like to contact us directly about the Safe Harbor program, please send an e-mail to [safeharbor@monster.com](mailto:safeharbor@monster.com). 

**Changes to Privacy Statement**

If we decide to change the substance of our Privacy Statement for Monster, we will post those changes through a prominent notice on the web site so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it. If at any time, you have questions or concerns about Monster's Privacy Statement, please feel free to email us at [info@monster.co.uk](mailto:info@monster.co.uk). 

**Legal and Contact Information**

Your data is submitted to Monster Worldwide Limited but is hosted and stored in a database on servers situated in the United Stated owned and maintained by Monster Worldwide Technologies LLC, a Delaware corporation whose principal place of business is at 622 Third Avenue, New York 10017, New York, USA. Monster is a name under which Monster, Inc., a Delaware corporation with its principal place of business at 5 Clock Tower Place, Maynard, MA 01754, USA and certain of its affiliated companies (meaning entities that control, are controlled by or are under common control with Monster, Inc.) do business on a worldwide basis. Monster Inc. is the data controller of all data stored in the Monster database however Monster.co.uk is also a data controller in relation to your personal data provided to Monster.co.uk. 

If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement or believe that we have not adhered to this Privacy Statement, please feel free to email us at [info@monster.co.uk](mailto:info@monster.co.uk) or contact us at Monster.co.uk at Chancery House, 53-64 Chancery Lane, London WC2A 1QS. We will use reasonable efforts to answer promptly your question or resolve your problem. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry, or if your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact Evan Kornrich at Monster Worldwide Inc., 622 Third Avenue, NY, NY 10017, USA, or +1 212-351-7028 or [evan.kornrich@monster.com](mailto:evan.kornrich@monster.com). to resolve your concerns. 

**Use of Cookies Statement**

Monster uses "cookies" to help personalise and maximise your online experience and time online. A cookie is a text file that is either stored in your computer’s memory temporarily (a “session” cookie) or placed on your hard drive (a “persistent” cookie) by a web page server. Cookies are not used to run programmes or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and your computer and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. When you return to the Monster site, cookies enable us to retrieve the information you previously provided, so you can easily use the features that you customised. For example, if you personalise Monster pages, or register for services, a cookie helps us to recall your specific information (such as user name, password and preferences). 

We predominately use “session” cookies which are not stored on your hard drive. Session cookies expire after two hours of inactivity or when you close your browser. Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster and more accurate results and a more personalised site experience. When you carry out a job search or apply online a large amount of data is processed by our system and transferred through each page of the search or application process. This information includes your job search criteria, data which identifies your CV, covering letter, the job you are applying for, your right to work in the relevant country and the results of any questionnaire you have completed as part of the online application process as well as demographic information that is not unique to you. “Session” cookies allow us to keep track of this data until you have completed your search or application. We also use cookies to identify users who have been banned from using our forums for behaviour which contradicts our terms of use and to track click streams, for load balancing and to enable you to navigate through the site using redirection pages. 

We use “persistent” cookies primarily to ensure that we do not show you pages that you have already seen and to personalise your site experience and save you time. “Persistent” Cookies enable us to recognise whether you have responded to any poll or seen an advertisement or information notice placed on the site so that we do not show you the poll, advertisement or notice again the next time you visit our site. If you have an alliance arrangement in place with Monster we also use “persistent” cookies to recall your alliance status and display your correct pricing information when you access our site. If you register on our site by using your Microsoft Passport user name and password a “persistent” cookie allows us to access and store information in your Passport account profile so you can login to our site faster. This information is treated in accordance with the policies and practices described in our Privacy Statement above. The “persistent” cookies we use will remain on your computer after you have left our site and will expire when you log out of the Site or 60 days after your last visit for security cookies, 90 days after your last visit for poll response and alliance cookies, one year after your last visit for Microsoft passport user cookies or two years after your last visit for advertisement and information notice cookies. 

We also use persistent third party cookies as part of online advertising campaigns to determine and track site traffic landing from Monster’s advertising banners that have been placed on the websites of third parties. The data collected via these cookies is anonymous and the information is not personal identifiable. The “persistent” cookies placed by our third party ad servers will remain on your computer after you have left our site for up to 20 years. You will find additional information about our third party ad servers at [www2.doubleclick.com/uk/privacy](http://www2.doubleclick.com/uk/privacy)and [www.atlassolutions.com/privacy](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy). 

If you do not want data to be collected about your use of our website you may click on the opt-put buttons listed below: [www.atlassolutions.com/opting.aspx?cookieStatus=optOut](http://www.atlassolutions.com/opting.aspx?cookieStatus=optOut)

In addition, third party advertisers on the web site may use “cookies”. Monster has no control over, and is not responsible for, the practices of those third party advertisers. Monster encourages you to review the policies of such advertisers. 

Monster is a name under which Monster, Inc., a Delaware corporation with its principal place of business at 5 Clock Tower Place, Maynard, MA 01754, USA and certain of its affiliated companies (meaning entities that control, are controlled by or are under common control with Monster, Inc.) do business on a worldwide basis. 

You may have the ability to accept or decline cookies at any time. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline all cookies if you prefer. Alternatively, you may be able to modify your browser setting to notify you each time a cookie is tendered and permit you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis. If you choose to decline cookies, however, that may hinder performance and negatively impact your experience on the web site.

The main browser types are listed below. If you have a different browser type, please refer to the ‘Help’ file or your handbook. 

**Windows PC**

**Internet Explorer 6.0**

Choose Tools and then Internet Options  
Click the Privacy tab  
Move the slider to choose your preferred settings   
The default setting is medium and the menu allows you to select the level of "filtering" on the basis of (a) the source of the cookie and (b) whether the source has a privacy policy  
For more specialised cookie settings click on Advanced

**Internet Explorer 5.0**

Choose Tools and then Internet Options  
Click the Security tab  
Select Internet, then Custom Level  
Choose one of the options 

**Internet Explorer 4.0**

Choose View and then Internet Options  
Click the Advanced tab  
Scroll down to the yellow exclamation icon under Security and choose one of the three options (accept or reject cookies or warn before accepting cookies)

**Internet Explorer 3.0**

Choose View, then Options and Advanced  
You can click on the Warn Before Accepting Cookies command 

**Mozilla**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu  
Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Mozilla Firebird 0.7**

Click on Tools, then Options  
Select the Privacy icon in the left-hand panel  
Click on Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings 

**Netscape Navigator 7**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu  
Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Netscape Navigator 6**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu  
Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Netscape Navigator 4**

Go to the task bar and click Edit  
Click Preferences and Advanced, and then choose your options in the Cookies box

**Opera**

Click on the File menu on the Opera tool bar  
Go to Preferences at the bottom of the File menu  
Click Privacy and select one of the available options  
Apple Macintosh

**Internet Explorer 5 (MacOS X)**

Choose Preferences from Explorer menu  
Select Receiving Files options  
Select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Internet Explorer 5 (MacOS 9)**

Choose Preferences from Edit menu  
Select Receiving Files options  
Select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Mozilla**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu  
Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Netscape Navigator 7**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu  
Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Netscape Navigator 6**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu  
Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies  
Choose your preferred settings

**Safari 1.0 (MacOS X)**

Choose Preferences from Safari menu  
Select Security icon  
Cookie settings are shown in window  
Choose your preferred settings

Thank you for using Monster.

Update effective 1 July 2006
